Adding an application into Aosp build system is pretty straightforward.
Let's have a look at the steps to add Java and Kotlin apps to the Aosp build system.
There are two ways to add apps.
One is to add the complete project with the source code into the Aosp build system.
The second option is to add a compiled APK file, so that means you will create the project in a separate
IDE.
For example, Android studio and you will build the project and make the APK and only move the APK into
the Aosp folder.
So in this session we are going to look at point one and see how to add a complete Android project with
source code into aosp.
The reason why we cannot simply copy the Android project directly into Aosp is due to the fact that
both uses different build system.
As we know, the Android application uses gradle build system and Aosp uses the song build system.
These two build systems are not compatible with each other.
That's the reason we have to do some manual migration steps in between.
So these are the steps to migrate an Android project into Aosp.
So first step is to restructure the folders.
That means we need to just extract the Java or Kotlin source folders and the resource folders from the
Android project and rest of the Gradle files are not necessary for aosp.
Second step the same android manifest dot xml can be copied into the Aosp folders.
It doesn't need any changes.
Third step is to write the song build scripts.
So we need to write the standard BP file for the new project or the module we are going to add.
First step include the new module or the project in corresponding build scripts.
In the next sessions, we will do a couple of practical sessions to add a Kotlin and Java project into
Aosp.
So I am using the Android automotive build in this case, but the overall steps which we are following
in these sessions are similar for other builds as well.
So in case if you have a foreign build, please follow the similar steps and it should go fine.